basictalk.com 2016-03-14

# BasicTalk | Privacy Policy

BasicTalk™ is committed to your privacy. We obey all laws and regulations in the United States applicable to our use and disclosure of your information. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will not trade, sell, or disclose to any third party any form of PII (as defined below) without your consent and we will not disclose or make available any PII to any third parties seeking to market third party products without your consent. We have set forth this Privacy Policy to explain to you how we collect and use information from our customers who use services and products from BasicTalk ("Customers") and from visitors to our Web sites and from potential customers who have communicated, made contact, or interacted with BasicTalk ("Visitors"), both in connection with online and offline services and products offered by BasicTalk.

**Collection of Information**

BasicTalk shall collect personally identifiable information, including but not limited to name, physical address, email address, telephone number, credit card information, and other personal information (collectively, "PII"), from Customers when initiating service and in connection with the provision or marketing of products and services. BasicTalk may collect PII from Visitors in connection with any visit to our Web sites, any communication about our services and products, or other transactions or interactions with BasicTalk.

BasicTalk may also collect non-personally identifiable information from Customers and Visitors regarding usage of our services or our Web site ("Non-PII"). Non-PII may include Web site pages viewed, time spent using certain services, demographic data, cookies, and other information which does not specifically identify any one individual.

"Cookies" are pieces of information that may be placed on your computer by a Web site for the purpose of facilitating and enhancing your communication and interaction with that Web site. Many Web sites use cookies for these purposes. We may use cookies to customize your visit to our Web sites and for other purposes to make your visit more convenient or to enable us to enhance our service.

In addition to our cookies, we and our vendors and contractors may also use clear gifs, Web beacons, and third party cookies to improve the performance of our Web sites, provide certain features such as advertising, or to anonymously track usage of our Web sites and the online activity of users. In addition, we may use such devices in our HTML-based emails to track the usage of such emails in much the same manner as usage of our Web sites is tracked.

You may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer, including third party cookies, or flush them from your browser by adjusting your Web browser preferences, in which case you may still use our Web site, but it may interfere with some of its functionality.

**Anti-Spyware Policy**

BasicTalk believes that Spyware is a threat to consumer privacy and a consumer's experience online. Therefore, we forbid any BasicTalk employee, agent, partner, affiliate, or contractor from intentionally deploying or using Spyware (as defined in this policy) on behalf of BasicTalk. Spyware refers to any executable software application that is installed on a user's personal computer and covertly gathers and transmits PII through the user's Internet connection without the knowledge or consent of the user. Cookies and Web beacons are not considered Spyware. Spyware may gather PII, such as e-mail addresses and credit card information, and may even alter personal computer settings. Intentional use of Spyware by any BasicTalk employee, agent, partner, or affiliate on BasicTalk's behalf will not be tolerated and will be considered grounds for dismissal, contract termination, and/or loss of payment.

**Use of Information**

BasicTalk will use PII to (1) market products and services to Customers and Visitors that BasicTalk believes may be of interest to them, (2) provide services and products requested by Customers and Visitors and (3) enable its vendors, partners to provide and assist BasicTalk in the provision of such services and products to BasicTalk, Customers, or Visitors or to participate in joint marketing offers with BasicTalk. In our contracts with vendors, contractors and partners, we require them to protect PII and to limit their use of such information to the purposes for which it is provided. They may not use this information for their own independent marketing purposes. If you purchase products and services offered jointly by BasicTalk and one of our partners, PII may be received and shared by both BasicTalk and our partner. Each company's privacy policy may apply. However, we will not share your credit card information with any third parties unless they are involved in processing payments for services that you have purchased from BasicTalk. BasicTalk only works with partners whom we believe maintain high standards with respect to privacy and consumer rights.

BasicTalk may also use and disclose PII to investigate and help prevent potentially unlawful activity or activities that threaten the integrity of our service or network, to investigate fraud or violations of our [Terms of Service](https://www.basictalk.com/tos), as required by courts or administrative agencies or in connection with a sale, merger, or reorganization of BasicTalk's business.

**CPNI**

In the course of providing services to you, we collect and maintain certain customer proprietary network information ("CPNI"). CPNI includes the types of services you currently purchase, related usage and billing information for those services. Your telephone number, name, and address are not CPNI. We value our relationships with our customers and are committed to respecting and protecting your CPNI. Accordingly, we do not sell, trade, or share your CPNI, including your calling records outside of BasicTalk or with anyone not authorized to offer our products or services, or to perform functions on our behalf except as authorized by you or required by law. Generally, we can use your CPNI to offer additional services to you, and for billing and collections purposes. We can also disclose your CPNI for legal or regulatory reasons, including in response to subpoenas and court orders, without your prior knowledge or consent. We can also use CPNI to investigate fraud and to prevent violation of our Terms of Service and unlawful use of our network and services.

**Security**

BasicTalk has invested and deployed a wide variety of technology and security features to make reasonable efforts to ensure the privacy of information on its network. In addition, BasicTalk has implemented operations guidelines to ensure Customer and Visitor privacy is safeguarded throughout its organization. BasicTalk will continue to revise policies and implement additional security features as new technologies become available. However, no system or service can give a 100% guaranty of security, especially a service that relies upon the public Internet. Therefore, you acknowledge the risk that third parties may gain unauthorized access to your information when using or accessing our services and our network.

**Communications**

BasicTalk will not read, listen to or disclose to any third parties private e-mail, conversations, or other communications that are transmitted using BasicTalk services except as required to ensure proper operation of services or as otherwise authorized by law, or with your prior consent. Your call(s) may be monitored or recorded for quality assurance or training purposes.

You should be aware that any PII which you voluntarily include and transmit through publicly accessible forums (i.e., such as chat rooms, blogs, instant messages, listservs) may be viewed and used by anyone with access to such forums. BasicTalk is unable to control such uses of your PII, and by using such services, you assume the risk that the PII provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties.

**Account Information**

Subject to certain security requirements, BasicTalk will do its best to honor requests from Customers for their own account information, including name, address, company, or billing information. The Customer is responsible for ensuring that the information on file with BasicTalk is current and accurate.

**Children's Privacy Policy**

BasicTalk does not sell products or services for purchase by children. BasicTalk does not knowingly solicit or collect PII from children or teenagers under the age of eighteen. If you believe that a minor has disclosed PII to BasicTalk, [report this to us](https://support.basictalk.com/app/ask).

**BasicTalk Spam Policy**

BasicTalk has zero tolerance for spam. Spam complaints will be dealt with seriously and can result in losing BasicTalk privileges including but not limited to loss of a customer's account. If you receive spam and want to report it to BasicTalk, please forward the email you have received to [spam-police@basictalk.com](mailto:spam-police@basictalk.com)

**Third Party Web Sites and Services**

Our service may contain links to other Web sites and services not maintained by BasicTalk. In addition, other Web sites and services may also reference or link to BasicTalk. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our service, or surf the Internet, and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site and service that you visit. We do not endorse, screen, or approve, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of, such other Web sites and services.

BasicTalk does not assume, and expressly disclaims, any liability for third parties that have been provided with information as permitted by this Privacy Policy or who have collected information as permitted by this Privacy Policy (such as advertisers using third party cookies).

**Opt-out Policy**

If you do not want your PII used by BasicTalk for any direct marketing purposes, then you may opt-out of such disclosures by sending an email via [https://support.basictalk.com/app/ask](https://support.basictalk.com/app/ask).

However, we are not responsible for removing your PII from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this policy. Since BasicTalk must use a Customer's PII in order to provide them with BasicTalk services, Customers cannot opt-out of all uses of their PII unless they cancel their service.

**Changes to Policy**

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time by posting such changes here. You should review this policy regularly for changes, and can easily see if changes have been made by checking the Effective Date below. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use PII in a way that differs from this policy, we will post such changes here and provide you the opportunity to opt-out of such differing uses. Your continued use following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes.

**Terms of Service**

For Customers, this Privacy Policy is subject to the BasicTalk Terms of Service or other agreements between you and BasicTalk. If you are a Customer, please refer to the Terms of Service or such other agreements regarding certain rights and limitations with respect to your use of BasicTalk's services.

**United States of America**

Our service is maintained in the United States of America. By using our services, you authorize the export of PII to the USA and its storage and use by BasicTalk or its vendors, contractors and partners, anywhere in the world, as specified in this policy.

**Effective Date**

This Privacy Policy was last updated on April 18, 2013.
